[Music]
hello and welcome to this session about
Microsoft co-pilot in Dynamics 365
business Central co-pilot is the AI
powered assistant for work that helps
boost creativity it helps improve
productivity and eliminates those
tedious tasks so you can really focus on
what matters for your business and now
in 2024 release wave 1 co-pilot also
assists with analytical tasks uh my name
is Mike borj Cardon I'm a product
manager at Microsoft and today I'm
joined by my colleagues Thomas and Kenny
hello my name is Thomas Jensen I'm a
software engineer on the business
Central Development team and my name is
Kenny paban I am also a product manager
in the business Central product group
and uh in very short video we're going
to show you how co-pilot can help with
uh specific analytical tasks for your
organization uh we're going to share
some practical tips so you can get the
most out of this uh and also help you
get started so you can get Hands-On and
try this out um but let's just uh take a
moment to understand U Kenny generally
speaking how do our customers get to
Data Insights today that's a great
question Mike so we have this bi
triangle that where we describe typical
analytics needs in an organization and
they really change with the way you work
with the role you have if you are in the
leadership you typically want aggregated
data if you are typically in a middle
management position this is why you have
these ad hoc analysis tasks like your
boss com in and ask how many teddy bears
did we sell in Greece last year compared
to something like that and you don't
have a report for that right so that's
why we built the data analysis tools on
lists last year to help with this dat at
analysis we also have normal reports um
of course now um with data analysis or
with ad hog analysis it's it's typical
that it starts with data Savvy people
like controllers they like to like group
data Maybe th throw in a bunch of pivos
and and and do that right but what we
discovered was that's not it's not a
task that is easy for everyone to do
pivot tables so so that's why we thought
could we make it easier for the the
normal users to also do ad hoc analysis
and that's why we're excited to announce
the public preview of analysis assist um
here co-pilot uh you know with this new
capability helps uh reduce the time it
takes to get to identifying Trends uh
anomalies in your business data uh
simply using the power of of your own
words basically so for example you may
be totaling up transactions uh in
preparation for next year's budget
budget you may be identifying gaps in uh
your inventory uh so you can plan how to
distribute things better you may be
looking for specific sales or purchase
transactions as well so by describing in
a simple sentence how you want to
structure your data uh you quickly get
to insights instead of spending the time
and effort on the clicks and keystrokes
to actually lay out data in front of you
on your screen in the uh analysis tabs
uh and you can do this without ever
leaving business Central without the
need for for context switching uh across
different apps and ultimately uh it
makes these Advanced Analytical tools
and capabilities in business Central uh
a lot easier which means uh more people
across the organization can uh make
datadriven decisions themselves so how
about we take a look at how this works
Thomas would you like to give us a demo
yes of course I will so let's switch to
our our screen here and uh to show you
the new functionality let's take a look
at the the item list of course it's
important to notice that this
functionality does not only work on the
item list it actually works on any list
that already supports uh analyzing data
but uh but let's try the the item list
so what you'll notice here is there's a
new co-pilot menu at the top and in that
we have a analyze list action let's try
that and then a window pops up where
co-pilot will now ask us uh to put in
some words on what kind of analysis we
would actually like uh so let's try with
something simple first let's just add a
few columns to a our analysis for
instance we want to show you the the the
item description maybe we want some
onand
information about the items and let's
add the the unit cost as
well and then we click the generate and
let's see what happens then things get
sent off to the co-pilot it will do it
magic
and eventually it will come up with a
new tab that gets inserted with the
information we ask for so we ask for the
description some onhand information
which ends up being the the quantity on
hand field and then the unit
cost and what you can see here they
actually also generated a title for the
tab it inserted sort of based on the
summary of of what we asked for and you
can also see it has a dotted line uh
that means that this tab has not been
saved yet it's in draft mode
and you can of course modify this even
further and to do that we have uh moved
the window at the bottom so we can
actually better see uh what was uh
generated for this analysis but it also
allows us to add some further
adjustments to this so for instance we
could choose to uh so let's sort the
this list by by the by the cost so let's
say we want to
short the unit cost cost and let's do it
descending and then it will run
again and it will add the Sorting now so
we have the the biggest number at the
top pretty easy of course you can also
do this by hand but uh but it's if you
don't really know where to click it's
much easier just to to tell it what you
want so now we have two iterations of
this tab that was generated the first
one with the three columns the second
one where we also added sorting and you
can see that in the dialogue here this
says two of two uh and if you change
your mind and you don't want the Sorting
anyway you can just click the the back
arrow go back to the first
iteration if the more want to use that
or you can go ahead and again to the to
the second one so you can always skip
back and forth between the different
iterations uh of the analysis you have
created uh to make it a little more
advanced let's try to uh to take away
some of the items so for instance we we
only want to to show the the the items
that have a replacement so let's say
show only items with
a
replacement and oh that was actually
misil the replacement anyway let's try
to see whether C pilot can figure that
out
anyway it should be able to figure that
out and you can actually see that now it
added a filter to take a way the ones
that don't have a replacement you can
also see in the in the name it actually
figured out even though I misspelled
replacement it figured out the right
word to put in there and if you want to
take a look at what was actually
generated or created for us we can go to
the filter and see that even though we
ask for
replacement we can actually see there's
no field or column called replacement
but there's one called substitution so
copilot figured out that replacement
substitution that's sort of the same so
let's add a filter to substitution exist
and set it to yes and that's what we're
seeing now so now we added columns we
added sorting and we added some
filtering and if we're happy with that
we can just click the keyid if we don't
like it we can discard it but for now
let's choose to keep it because this was
actually the way we want to analyze our
data but of course there's more than
that so let's try to create a new
one uh and if you're not really sure how
to start phrasing what you want there's
a prompt guide here where you can
actually see different suggestions we
have so you can do grouping and pivoting
and you can showing your Fields you can
also do sorting and filtering and then
at the end there's something where you
can freeze your columns or you can
rename the actual tab let's try to do
one with with grouping so let's say we
want to group by the vendor so we'll
just tell it to group by the vendor and
let's see what it gets generated from
that so it actually found the the vendor
number and then did a grouping on that
it chose to also add the description
sort of we can see which
items um belongs to this vendor and then
of course also the
type and that's actually close to what
we wanted U but maybe we weren't that
happy with the with the group by vendor
name so let me change that so let's tell
it to to rename the tab so we can for
instance call it the items prenter
instead and then it will rename the tab
for us as you can see we still have the
dotted underline meaning that this tab
has not been saved yet it's still in
this draft mode where we can refine
it and this is actually what I want or
at least it's close to so I can choose
to click the key bit uh
but before doing that I actually want to
get rid of the type because I actually
only want the vendor number and the
description so of course I could uh tell
co-pilot to remove the type column
another option is actually just to find
the column out here and then just say we
want to remove that what happens when I
do this is that we will sort of commit
the draft uh tab we have do the change
you ask for and then take the dialogue
away so let me try to click over here
you will see that the tab type column
went away the dialog closed and the tab
is now fully safe because it has the
solid line so this was sort of some of
the details you can do with the with the
co-
pilet Thomas that's great um isn't it it
it's actually fantastic I'm wondering is
this are we sending a lot of data to
like the customer data to to co-pilot to
generate this that's a really really
good Chris yes of course we don't send
any of your data to co-pilot because
that's not what's needed the only thing
we actually send to co-pilot is the
description of which columns are
available on your list and based on that
information copilot generates an
analysis and then after that data gets
filled into that nice so there's no uh
no risk in leaking your data in any
way so I really like it Thomas but it
also feels like your demo is very
mechanic like you show the features
goodby yes so
could you show like show us the money
here like I want to know what my
customers owe me can you do that for me
can help me answer that question let for
that so for inst maybe we could use the
customer ler interviews for that let's
go to that
list uh and let create a new tab and you
wanted something that show show me what
my customers owe me show me what my let
me try that what my customers
that and that's interesting here because
now we haven't specified which columns
to do anything with no filtering or
anything we just in a natural language
sentence told copile what we wanted and
uh now it comes back wow with an
analysis with the costomer name the
amount and the remaining
amount fantastic it's almost what I want
but it seems like this is for each
invoice or maybe you can can we just
group it by customer or yeah maybe we
could we could at least take away the
the amount column because you actually
you only wanted the the the remaining
amount so let's say
remove amount column but what if we add
some information on when these money I
actually want to know when when the
payments are due so maybe due month and
year or yeah for instance and then show
let's to show
the due year perhaps and maybe the
months as well
yeah nice
so it's almost what I want um except
would be nice to I'm a pivot kind of guy
I I want actually these as columns
instead of um like real pivot columns do
that let's ask whether we could get it
as a pivot and maybe we should then move
the the date to the top so we can
actually Group by them that would be
nice
see so let's see what happens
now this seems close what you wanted you
got a pivo you got your dates at the top
but got a lot of measures here can can
we clean that up as well maybe there's a
bit too many didn't want all of them
okay uh so copilot was a bit creative
and thought you actually wanted all of
them so of course we can ask co-pilot to
take them away again there's also
another option we can maybe it's in this
case it's it's easier just to do it
manually so we can here just go and
remove the one we actually do not want
so you actually wanted the the remaining
amount yeah so let's keep
that
and we now have that and maybe we should
also size it a bit so you can actually
that's nice to see so now you're pretty
close to what you ask that's not even
close Thomas this is exactly what I
wanted and you know I kind of like the
idea that co-pilot helped me get started
with my analysis but in the end I was in
control I kind of finish it up did my
things and and kind of made that human
human element and approved the analysis
that's fantastic and I love how just a
few words is all it took really to draft
all of this uh content on screen now
it's important to understand how this
works as well um the data needed to
answer these kind of questions happen to
be on this list so I want you to
understand that co-pilot at this stage
in preview will only work with fields
that are shown on the page on the list
page itself um and if you ask for other
fields that are not there or on the
table uh co-pilot will not be able to
bring them into that analysis tab uh
similarly co-pilot will not stretch
across different tables to join them
together uh to bring data together that
way uh so it's important to know this
now uh co-pilot here and the ability to
analyze that list is available on all
virtually all list pages and I believe
worksheets as well in business Central
uh including your custom list so if
you've created a custom list page with
your own you know information in there
such as the the list of vehicles for
example as part of uh customizations on
your environment or something that comes
with an add-on solution as well uh this
just works at no additional effort from
your part in fact you know as long as
the user has permission to analyze uh or
the page allows analysis U you'll Now
find co-pilot on that
page uh a few more tips here to
understand um you know how to use this
and where to use this so first of all
co-pilot in business Central is
available exclusively for business
Central online so that's where you'll
find this new capability um this has
been released with 2024 release Wave 1
so you'll need to upgrade to version
24.0 or later later um it's also being
rolled out for uh all environment
localizations with the exception of
Canada for regulatory reasons um it's
also available in preview in English
language only so you'll need to make
sure that my settings indicate that your
user is running with one of these
languages on screen and finally one of
the very common questions that we get
how much does this cost uh well at this
stage co-pilot is available uh with your
business Central license at no
additional cost
cost um now we designed this feature
really from from the ground up uh on
Microsoft's values and responsible AI
standards and in fact the Microsoft
cloud runs on trust this is something
we've we've always said from the very
beginning of the cloud um and really our
approach to AI here is is no different
uh so our promise to our customers is
that their data is their data we do not
use that data to train the AI models to
the benefit of others in this case and
as Thomas mentioned men earlier uh we
we're not sending all of that data over
to Azure
openai um now uh you're also protected
at every step with you know the security
privacy and compliance controls that you
expect and admins are in control in this
case as well um and uh you know we every
co-pilot feature of Microsoft including
this one is built very thoughtfully uh
to make sure our customers are safe and
their data remain safe so for example uh
when you put co-pilot to work here it
only has access to the the lists the
fields and the data that um that you as
a user have access to and really the
only thing that's generated is that
layout of information no new data is
generated in this case um and uh all of
those things help ensure that it's you
know it's as accurate as possible in
terms of what is what is generated in
that analysis Tab and finally AI is
sometimes Incorrect and that's why we
always give our users the opportunity to
review what co-pilot has generated
before for committing it and fully
saving it uh into business
Central So you you're probably wondering
um you know if you're a partner how do I
try this out how do I get handson and
how do I demo it to my customers uh well
that's super simple for demos we always
recommend CDX uh customer digital
experiences so if you just go to aka.ms
CDX you can sign in with your partner
identity uh and then with just a few
clicks you can get your own tenant your
own environment a business Central if
you sign up for a business Central uh
free trial uh in that tenant um once
you're there uh you are ready to
experience analysis assist with co-pilot
um if you don't see it in that
environment there's a few things you can
watch out for so first of all check the
co-pilot and AI capabilities page we've
created this single simple space for
admins to go in and be able to find
which exactly which co-pilot
capabilities are in my environment um so
we give that trans transparency but also
control so you may need to check uh is
this particular um feature uh is it
active or it hasn't been deactivated in
there that might be why you don't see it
in the environment uh the other thing to
watch out for here is that because Azure
open AI service is only available in uh
certain regions but not all some of our
customers on some environments will need
to opt in to um having data move outside
of the geographic boundary uh which is a
switch you see on the screen right here
um and when you do that not just this
feature but all the co-pilot
capabilities should light up in that
environment uh if you still don't see uh
analysis assist in your environment
there a few more things you can check
make sure your language is set to
English in my settings make sure you've
upgraded to version 24 or later of
course and check the permission set so
there's a permission set which governs
whether as a user you can or cannot
generally analyze lists in business
Central as well
when you do get in there and have the
opportunity to try it out uh please
please please send us your feedback help
us improve uh this experience and help
us improve co-pilot um so you know you
can use the like and dislike buttons in
the actual uh dialogue itself um that
feedback is really important to us it
helps us continue evolving and improving
co-pilot in general so we really
appreciate if you take the time to to
give us that
feedback Okay so there's so much more
co-pilot in this wave uh and in fact
there's um a whole bunch of sessions we
recommend that you go take a look at uh
you know co-pilot is helping our users
uh get more efficient with entering
sales lines and their sales documents uh
you can chat with co-pilot to find data
in business Central but also learn new
skills and ask about how to do things or
explain Concepts uh and we're also
helping with uh electronic invoice
matching as well uh on top of that Kenny
I believe we have also some really
interesting sessions on analytics as
well true so in in the the 2024 release
wave one we have new Excel reports for
finance and sales so there's a session
for that and you know what we even added
a little bit of excel co-pilot in there
so if you want to have a a taste of that
uh go check it out now to build these
multilanguage Excel reports we also
added new capabilities in the Excel
layout feature so there's a a partner or
a developer part of the that story as
well in a session called Excel layouts
for developers so go check that out as
well fantastic and great to hear there's
more Microsoft copilot showing up oh
yeah and more of our videos there uh but
if you want to learn more about co-pilot
uh here's a couple of resources that you
can follow um the partner pitch deck uh
has some fantastic slides you can use
with your customers and that's been
updated to include AI as well so
definitely go check it out and of course
check out our documentation for more
tips and examples and information about
how analysis assist works in business
Central for those of you who are
completely new to business Central uh
there's plenty of resources to help you
get engaged uh you can follow us on
social media you can you know engage
directly with the product team as well
uh and share your feedback and valuable
ideas so I think we can wrap that up
congratulations you've reached the end
of this video uh we hope you found this
informative um I'm really eager to hear
your feedback and what you do with these
new capabilities for co-pilot in
business Central so on behalf of the
team that worked on this um thank you uh
and uh thanks for
watching